Guide to the Paul Kagan Utopian Communities Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Paul Kagan Research Files, 1845-1980; Series IV; 4.3' (16 boxes)
  - FOUNTAINGROVE
    - Printed Material
      - Illustration of Fountaingrove Vineyards Residence and Office (Box 23, Folder 367)
      - Fountaingrove Vineyard Co. pamphlets and wine labels, 1938, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 368)
    - Other Papers
      - Postcard to Mr. T. Ijicki at Fountaingrove Vineyards from S. Sonoda, Korea (in Korean?), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 369)
      - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 370)
      - Robert Hine's notes (photocopy), 1971 Jan (Box 23, Folder 371)
        For reference use only. May not be reproduced
      - Pencil drawing of the Fountaingrove winery, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 372)
  - HALCYON
    - Photographs
      - Vintage Prints
        - Contact prints of glass plate negatives of depictions of unidentified people, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 373)
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of Halcyon people, buildings and landscapes: positives, 1970, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 374-375)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folders 763-764
        - Views of Halcyon people, buildings and landscapes: negatives, [1970], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 376)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives from Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints from the Bancroft Library, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 377)
        - Copy prints and negatives from the Temple of the People (Box 23, Folder 378)
        - Copy negatives from UCLA, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 379)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives
        - May include copy prints from vintage photographs above
        - Copy prints from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 380)
        - Copy negatives from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 381)
    - Other Papers
      - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 382)
      - Robert Hine's notes: printed material and correspondence relating to Halcyon (Box 23, Folder 383)
      - Forgostein, Harold E., "Concerning the Temple of the People," typescript, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 384)
      - Photographic plate, "Eleventh Annual Convention of Temple Members", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 385)
  - HOLY CITY
    - Photographs
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of Holy City buildings, 1970
          See: Oversize, box 44, folders 765-768
        - Negatives, [1970 Feb] (Box 23, Folder 386)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives of Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints and negatives from the Bancroft Library (Box 23, Folder 387)
        - Copy prints from the Los Angeles Times, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 388)
        - Copy prints and negatives from the San Francisco Chronicle (Box 23, Folder 389)
        - Copy prints and negatives from Wide World Photos (Box 23, Folder 390)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives
        - May include copy prints from vintage photographs above
        - Copy prints from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 391-392)
        - Copy negatives from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 393)
    - Notes
      - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 394)
      - Ann Curtis' notes (photocopies), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 395)
      - Robert Hine's notes, including correspondence, writings, and printed material (photocopies) (Box 23, Folder 396)
    - Printed Material
      - Photocopies of clippings, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 397)
      - Photocopies of pamphlets, broadsides, ephemera by William Riker, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 398-399)
  - ICARIA SPERANZA
    - Photographs
      - Vintage Prints
        - Icaria Speranza, [ca. 1884-86] (Box 24, Folder 400)
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of buildings and a bridge, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 401)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folders 769-772
      - Copy Prints and Negatives of Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints from the Bancroft Library, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 402)
        - Copy prints from the Huntington Library, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 403)
      - Copy Prints
        - Copy prints from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 404)
    - Other Papers
      - ALS to administrators of Icaria Speranza from Alexis Marchand, 1886 [Jan 12] (Box 24, Folder 405)
      - Paul Kagan's research notes and drafts (Box 24, Folder 406)
      - Robert Hine's notes, including correspondence, biographical information relating to Icaria Speranza (photocopy), 1971 Jan (Box 24, Folder 407)
  - INTERNATIONAL RE-EDUCATION FOUNDATION
    - Photographs of people at the Foundation, [1972] (Box 24, Folder 408-409)
    - Paul Kagan's photographs of people and buildings of Mendocino Commune, Re-Educational Foundation (Booneville) (Box 24, Folder 410-412)
    - Pamphlets, mailings, and bulletins from the International Re-Education Foundation, 1970-[72] (Box 24, Folder 413)
    - The Universal Voice Vol IV, Nos. 1, 6, 10; Vol. V, Nos. 3-4, 1972 Jan-Jun
      See: Oversize, box 44, folder 773
  - KAWEAH
    - Photographs
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Kaweah buildings, n.d.
          See: Oversize, box 44, folder 774
      - Copy Prints and Negatives of Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints from the Bancroft Library, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 414)
        - Copy prints from unidentified source [Bancroft Library?], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 415)
    - Other Papers
      - Paul Kagan's research notes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 416)
      - Robert Hine's notes, including correspondence (photocopies) (Box 25, Folder 417)
      - Photocopies of correspondence, documents and clippings [from the Bancroft Library?] (Box 25, Folder 418)
        See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 714
      - Photographic plate of "A Real Log Cabin in Giant Forest" from Out West, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 419)
  - KROTONA AND OJAI VALLEY
    - Writings
      - [Aarondale, Dr.] "Ojai: A Cradle of the Future," typescript, [ca. 1930] (Box 25, Folder 420)
      - Besant, Annie
        - "A Lodge of the Theosophical Society," typescript, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 421)
        - "Memorandum on Krotona," typescript (Box 25, Folder 422)
      - Dyson, Verne, "Ready for the New Messiah," typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 423)
      - Hardy, Carlos S. "The Founding of Krotona," typescript carbon (Box 25, Folder 424)
      - Mayes, Catherine, "Ojai," (poem) typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 425)
      - Unidentified. "Krishnamurti: A Sketch of His Life and Ideas," typescript (Box 25, Folder 426)
    - Photographs and Postcards
      - Vintage Photographs
        - Krotona buildings and landscapes by Chas. W. Beam, 5070 Hollywood Blvd., L.A., [ca. 1912] (Box 25, Folder 427)
        - Krotona buildings by R. H. Stone, Los Angeles, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 428)
        - Portraits by Bryan-Brandenburg Co. Engravers, Electrotypers, Los Angeles, Calif.; Witzel, Los Angeles; W. Schrempf, Hollywood, Cal. (Box 25, Folder 429)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 775
        - Landscapes, people, buildings, [1910-36] (Box 26, Folder 430-438)
        - Landscapes, people, buildings, [1924], n.d. (Box 27, Folder 439-441)
        - Postcards and snapshots of people and landscapes originally housed in a folder labeled "Krotona -- Not Relevant" in Kagan's hand, 1924, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 442)
        - Disbound album of Krotona, [1911] (Box 27, Folder 443)
        - Album of Krotona, [1912-13] (Box 27, Folder 444)
        - Leaves disbound from an album of Krotona, [1912-13] (Box 28, Folder 445)
        - Album of Krotona, [1912]-16
          With two printed advertisements pasted in at back
          See: Oversize, box 45, folders 797-811
          See: Oversize, box 46, folders 812-824
        - Album of Krotona assembled by Grace S. Hall, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 446)
        - Contact prints of glass plate negatives of buildings at Krotona, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 447)
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of Krotona, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 448)
        - Views of Ojai people and landscapes (Box 28, Folder 449)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 776
      - Copy Prints and Negatives of Others
        - For reference use only. Do not reproduce
        - Copy prints from the Huntington Library, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 450)
      - Copy Prints
        - May include copy prints of vintage photographs
        - Copy prints from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 451-452)
    - Oral Histories
      - Robert Ellwood interview, 1971 Jan (Box 29, Folder 453)
      - [Rosalind] Rajagopal and Franklin Lacey interview (Box 29, Folder 454)
      - Art Wadsworth interview, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 455)
      - Betty Warrington interview, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 456)
    - Printed Material
      - The American Theosophist and the Theosophic Messenger, 1913 Jan (Box 29, Folder 457)
      - Besant, Annie. Esoteric Christianity Adyar, Madras, India: Theosophical Publishing House, 1913 (Box 29, Folder 458)
      - Blavatsky, H. P. and W. Q. Judge, Dreams Bombay: Theosophy Company (India) Ltd., 1947 (Box 29, Folder 459)
      - Bookmarks, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 460)
      - Happy Valley Foundation pamphlets and reports, 1970-75 (Box 29, Folder 461)
      - Happy Valley School pamphlets, 1949-71 (Box 29, Folder 462)
      - Judge, William Q. The Ocean of Theosophy Los Angeles: The Theosophy Company, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 463)
      - Krishnamurti, J. At the Feet of the Master Chicago: The Theosophical Press., n.d. (Box 29, Folder 464)
      - Theosophical Society pamphlets and newsletter, 1970-74 (Box 29, Folder 465-466)
      - World Institute of Avasthology newsletter and pamphlets, 1974-75 (Box 30, Folder 467)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1964-71 (Box 30, Folder 468)
      - Clippings, 1928-73 (Box 30, Folder 469)
    - Other Papers
      - Correspondence, 1912-71 (Box 30, Folder 470)
        Includes 3 postcards with views of Krotona buildings and people
      - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 471)
        Consists of 3 postcards with views of Krotona buildings
      - Diploma for Betty Robinson: Membership in The Theosophical Society, 1915 Nov 8 (Box 30, Folder 472)
      - Master mason's diploma for Betty S. Robertson, 1929 Feb 14
        See: Oversize, box 39, folder 715
      - Paul Kagan's notes, 1973, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 473)
      - Robert Hine's notes (photocopies), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 474)
      - Oil painting of Annie Besant, n.d. (Box 475 (Art))
      - Color prints of Krotona Court, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 476)
  - LAMA FOUNDATION
    - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 477)
    - Strategic plan chart, [1966]
      See: Broadside cabinet, folder 830
    - Paul Kagan's photographs of Lama Foundation buildings and people (Box 30, Folder 478)
    - Lama Foundation pamphlet (Box 30, Folder 479)
      Photographs and art by Paul Kagan
    - Pamphlets and broadsides from the Lama Foundation, [1969-74] (Box 30, Folder 480)
      See also: Broadside cabinet, folders 831-833
  - LLANO DEL RIO AND NEW LLANO
    - Photographs
      - Vintage Prints
        - Ernest S. Wooster's Collection, [1932], n.d. (Box 30, Folder 481-484)
          Note on accompanying envelope reads, "Photos from Wooster's Collection. Millsap cannot identify"
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of Llano del Rio people and buildings: positives (Box 30, Folder 485)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folders 777-779
        - Views of Llano del Rio people and buildings: negatives, [1970-72] (Box 30, Folder 486-487)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives from Others
        - For reference use only. Do not reproduce
        - Copy negative from the Bancroft Library, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 488)
        - Copy print and negative from the Huntington Library (Box 30, Folder 489)
        - Copy prints and negatives from the Los Angeles Times, 1949, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 490)
        - Copy negatives from UCLA, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 491)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives
        - May include copy prints and negatives of Walter Millsap photographs and printed material
        - Copy prints of Llano people, buildings, landscapes and printed material (Box 30, Folder 492-498)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 780
        - Copy negatives of Llano people, buildings, landscapes and printed material (Box 31, Folder 499-501)
    - Printed Material
      - Amoss, Jim. "The Lost Colony of Llano" Lagniappe, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 502)
      - Huxley, Aldous. "Ozymandias, the Utopia that Failed." Printed in Fortnight, Apr 27 1953 and Huxley's Tomorrow and Tomorrow and Tomorrow (photocopy) (Box 31, Folder 503)
        Accompanied by photocopy of letter from Millsap to O. D. Keep, editor of Fortnight, about the article
      - California Historical Society finding aid for Llano del Rio Cooperative Colony Records (photocopy) (Box 31, Folder 504)
      - Kapotsy, Albert Sr. "Consolidate or Suffer and Perish" (photocopy) (Box 31, Folder 505)
        Original dated Jan 1, 1969
      - First page of three Ernest S. Wooster articles in Sunset Magazine, Jul-Sep, 1924 (photocopy), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 506)
    - Other Papers
      - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 507)
      - Photocopy of letter from Millsap to Robert Hine, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 508)
      - Oral history transcript of Walter Millsap's statements recorded by Abe Hoffman, 1961 Dec 26 (Box 31, Folder 509)
  - PISGAH GRANDE
    - Oral Histories
      - John Bartleman interview, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 510)
      - Notes from interview with J. Runkle, 1971 Jan (Box 31, Folder 511)
      - H. J. Smith interview, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 512)
    - Printed Material
      - Advertisement in magazine, "Pisgah Store", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 513)
      - "Blest cloths" from Pisgah Grande and Pisgah in Tennessee, 1975, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 514)
        Six accompanied by letter from Dorothy E. Spalding to Paul Kagan, 1975 Jul 10
      - Funeral program for Nellie H. O'Neill, H. J. Smith officiating, 1975 May (Box 31, Folder 515)
      - Lea, Beverly, "Pisgah Grande," Ventura County Historical Society Quarterly, 1964 May (Box 31, Folder 516)
      - Repp, Ed Earl, "Gun-Toting Female Killer," Pioneer West, 1971 Apr (Box 31, Folder 517)
        Contains picture and quotes from Bill Stiles, last member of the James gang, Pisgah member
      - Photocopies of articles and book chapters relating to Pisgah (Box 31, Folder 518-519)
        Kagan noted that many of the originals of these are no longer available
    - Photographs
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - H. J. Smith and Pisgah buildings, 1970, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 520)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folders 781-785
      - Copy Prints and Negatives of Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints from the Huntington Library, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 521)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives
        - Copy prints from unidentified sources, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 522-523)
        - Copy negative from unidentified source, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 524)
    - Other Papers
      - Robert Hine's notes, including correspondence (photocopy) (Box 31, Folder 525)
      - Notes of Edwin H. Carpenter, on Pisgah research (photocopy), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 526)
      - Photocopies of L.A. Times memos, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 527)
      - "Pisgah Home" by H. C. D. Typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 528)
        Unpublished ms in L.A. Times Library
  - POINT LOMA
    - Photographs and Postcards
      - Vintage Prints
        - 2 photographs from the Loma Homestead Photographic Series. Views from the World's Theosophical Center of the Universal Brotherhood, Established at Point Loma, San Diego, Calif., in 1897, by Katherine Tingley (Box 31, Folder 529)
        - 8 photographs from the Lomaland Photographic Series. Views from the World's Center of the Universal Brotherhood and Theosophical Society, established at Point Loma, California, in 1900, by Katherine Tingley (Box 31, Folder 530)
        - Buildings, [1915-48], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 531)
        - People and performances of Greek plays (Box 31, Folder 532-535)
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of Point Loma people and buildings (Box 32, Folder 536)
          See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 786
      - Copy Prints of Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints from the Bancroft Library, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 537)
        - Copy prints from the California Western University Library, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 538)
        - Copy prints from the San Diego Historical Society (Box 32, Folder 539)
        - Copy prints from the Union Title Insurance Company, San Diego, California (Box 32, Folder 540)
      - Copy Prints
        - May include copy prints from vintage photographs
        - Copy prints from unidentified sources of buildings, people, printed material, landscapes, performances of Greek plays, [1971], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 541-544)
        - Copy negative from unidentified source, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 545)
    - Printed Material
      - Bruck, Connie, "Too Outrageous for Point Loma," Reader, 1973 Jul-Aug
        See: Oversize, box 44, folder 787
      - Christmas Greetings from the Cabinet Officers of the Universal Brotherhood and Theosophical Society (Box 32, Folder 546)
      - East-West Cultural Center, 1971-72 (Box 32, Folder 547)
      - Harris, Helen, ed. Katherine Tingley, Theosophical Leader and Teacher (Box 32, Folder 548)
      - Vonnegut, Kurt, Jr. "The Mysterious Madame Blavatsky" McCall's, 1970 Mar
        See: Oversize, box 44, folder 788
      - Miscellaneous Point Loma mailings, 1975, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 549)
      - Photocopies of articles and pamphlets relating to Point Loma history (Box 32, Folder 550-551)
    - Other Papers
      - Iverson Harris correspondence (Box 33, Folder 552)
      - Point Loma Publications, Inc. documents (photocopies), n.d. (Box 33, Folder 553)
      - Iverson Harris writings (carbons and photocopies) (Box 33, Folder 554)
      - Miscellaneous papers of Iverson Harris, 1971-75 (Box 33, Folder 555)
      - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 556)
      - Robert Hine's notes (photocopies), [1971 Jan] (Box 33, Folder 557)
      - Oral history transcript of Judith Tyberg interview, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 558)
      - Photocopies of photographs of Point Loma buildings and people (Box 33, Folder 559)
  - ROSICRUCIANS
    - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 560)
    - Robert Hine's notes and correspondence (photocopies) (Box 33, Folder 561)
    - Pamphlets about the Rosicrucian Fellowship, 1968, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 562-564)
  - SELF-REALIZATION FELLOWSHIP
    - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 565)
    - Clippings, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 566)
    - Pamphlets, 1957-69 (Box 33, Folder 567)
  - TASSAJARA ZEN MOUNTAIN CENTER
    - Photographs
      - Paul Kagan's Prints
        - Landscapes and portraits of people at Tassajara (Box 33, Folder 568)
        - Negatives: Views of a Be-in, [1967 Jan 14] (Box 33, Folder 569)
      - Copy Prints from Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints from the California Zen Center, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 570)
      - Copy Prints
        - Copy prints from an unidentified source, of Tassajara people, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 571)
    - Other Papers
      - List of items on loan to Paul Kagan, 1975 Jul-Aug (Box 33, Folder 572)
      - Photocopies of articles about Zen Center, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 573)
      - Pamphlets, notecards, and mailings from Zen Center, [1968-74] (Box 33, Folder 574)
  - VEDANTA SOCIETY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
    - Letter to Paul Kagan from Cliff Johnson, 1971 Feb 9 (Box 33, Folder 575)
      Accompanied by photocopy of part of a Vedanta pamphlet
    - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 576)
    - Notes of Arthur J. Wadsworth on Trabuco: correspondence, writings (photocopies), 1971 (Box 33, Folder 577)
    - Clippings, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 578)
    - Pamphlets and Vedanta mailings, 1956-71 (Box 33, Folder 579)
  - OTHER COMMUNES
    - Printed Material
      - Mailings, pamphlets, newspapers, and photocopies of articles about communes and related organizations beginning with letters A-B, 1974, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 580)
      - Pamphlets, articles, photocopies of articles about communes and related organizations beginning with letters C-K (Box 33, Folder 581)
        See also: Oversize, box 44, folders 789-790
      - Photocopies of articles and pamphlets about the Farallones Institute Integral Urban House (Box 33, Folder 582)
      - Mailings, pamphlets, articles, and photocopies of articles about communes and related organizations beginning with letters L-N, 1937-80 (Box 34, Folder 583)
      - Mailings and pamphlets about the Lemurian Fellowship, 1963-67 (Box 34, Folder 584)
      - Mailing and photocopy of article about communes and related organizations beginning with letters P-R (Box 34, Folder 585)
      - Pamphlets, newspaper, and broadside about Resource One, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 586)
        See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 791
      - Mailing, pamphlets, articles and photocopies of articles about communes and related organizations beginning with letters S-W (Box 34, Folder 587)
        See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 792
      - Pamphlets, broadsides about unidentified communes and related organizations, and photocopies of articles about communal living, 1967-[76] (Box 34, Folder 588)
        See also: Oversize, box 44, folder 793
      - Communal Studies Newsletter Philadelphia, 1976-77 (Box 34, Folder 589)
      - Communitas Yellow Springs, Ohio, 1972 Sep (Box 34, Folder 590)
      - Communities Louisa, Virginia, 1972, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 591)
      - Hays, Samuel P. "History and Genealogy: Patterns of Change and Prospects for Cooperation" Reprinted from Prologue, [1975] (Box 34, Folder 592)
      - Hine, Robert V. "Cult and Occult in California" Reprinted from The Pacific Spectator, [1954] (Box 34, Folder 593)
      - Magazine, The Modern Utopian, and newsletter published by Alternatives Berkeley, Calif., 1970-71 (Box 34, Folder 594)
      - New Age Voice, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 595)
      - Utopian Eyes Vol. 1, Issue 1-3, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 596)
      - The Imperial Family Bible, Containing the Old and New Testaments. Glasgow: Blackie and Son, Queen Street, 1845
        See: Oversize, box 47, folder 825
      - Miscellaneous journals, 1970, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 597)
    - Other Papers
      - Postcard to Mr. E. Sisaki, 1946 Mar 2 (Box 34, Folder 598)
      - "Child Rearing Practices of the Communal Family: Progress Report to NIMH," mimeograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 599)
      - Murphy, Michael. "Atheletes [sic] in the Games of Philosophy," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 600)
      - Negatives: Paul Kagan's views of people at Mesa Verde, [1968 Sep] (Box 34, Folder 601)
      - Contact prints made from glass plate negative of unidentified place, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 602)
      - Contact prints made from glass plate negative of unidentified people, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 603)
      - Paul Kagan's notes, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 604)
      - Sound recording: Joy to UC. Free Speech Carols, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 605)
      - Robert Hine's notes, correspondence, printed material (photocopies) relating to Tuolomne Co-Operative Farms, Inc. (Box 34, Folder 606)
- Paul Kagan's Writings, 1970-1976; Series V; 1.0' (3 boxes)
  Series V, Paul Kagan's Writings, is organized into two subseries: New World Utopias and Other Writings
  - NEW WORLD UTOPIAS
    - Correspondence
      - "A" general, 1972-74 (Box 35, Folder 607)
        - "B" general, 1970-75 (Box 35, Folder 608)
        - "C" general, 1971-74 (Box 35, Folder 609)
        - California Historical Society, 1971-74 (Box 35, Folder 610)
        - "D-E" general, 1971, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 611)
        - "F" general, 1971-72 (Box 35, Folder 612)